<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bad Archaeology</title>
    <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bad Archaeology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Shawn</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/details/shawn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/details/shawn/</guid>
      <description>Update stuff here? Or send it to the wiki</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/details/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/details/schedule/</guid>
      <description>We meet on Wednesdays, 11.35 - 2.25 in LA A204.
In general, our meetings will look like this:
Before class  read and annotate the introductory reading for the week&amp;rsquo;s theme use the weekly theme to find, read, and annotate two additional pieces add just one of those additional pieces to our shared Zotero library  nb: you can follow our hypothes.is group feed to find a reading; that is to say, it&amp;rsquo;s ok if multiple people read the same additional pieces</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/details/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/details/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>HIST 4805A: Bad Archaeology: The Trade in Human Remains &amp;amp; Other Antiquities By some reckonings, the economic value of the illegal trade in antiquities is on the same order of magnitude as that for drugs and weapons. This seminar will explore the 20th century history of looting, heritage crime, and the damage done by the wanton destruction of cultural heritage to feed this trade. It is offered in conjunction with the 2018 Shannon Lecture Series, ‘Bad Archaeology’ which explores the broader theme of the use and abuse of archaeological knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Research</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/details/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/details/research/</guid>
      <description>Second Term Research Projects The second term will be taken up largely with your own individual research projects. In exceptional circumstances, I&amp;rsquo;m willing to allow other configurations of work provided that the individuals involved work out in writing who will do what and who is going to be responsible for the overall management of the work.
In general
The projects should:
 address the core themes of this course demonstrate mastery over a body of material, in terms of the issues raised and the relevant scholarly literature make a new contribution to a body of research addressed in this course  The technical aspects</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bone Trade Project</title>
      <link>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/details/bonetrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shawngraham.github.io/bad-archaeology/details/bonetrade/</guid>
      <description>There is a thriving online trade in anatomical, ethnographic and archaeological human remains that makes ready use of new social media such as Instagram, Facebook, Etsy, and until recently, eBay. The “fetishization” of the ‘exotic’ dead that underpins this trade by its very nature transforms pieces of the body into material culture: curios, commodities or objets d’art. This practice has deep Colonial-era roots, but today’s e-commerce and social media platforms have only expanded collectors’ reach and made participation open to anyone with interest and spare finances.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>